American Philosophical Society Archives 1743-1984 APS.Archives
American Philosophical Society
- Communications, 1748-1837; III; 4.0 ln. ft.
  - Manuscript communications, 1748-1837; III.1; 3.5 ln. ft.
    - Report of Committee on Lime's Paper on Peach Trees, 1800 Oct. 2; 1.0 item; American Philosophical Society. (Box 1)
      For paper reported on see: Lime (pseud.), Concerning the Prevention of Decay in Peachtrees, 1797 Dec. 15
    - Report of Committee on the Preservation of Peach Trees, 1798 April 4; 1.0 item; American Philosophical Society. (Box 1)
      For papers reported on see: Lime (pseud.), Concerning the Prevention of Decay in Peach Trees, 1797 Dec. 15; and X (pseud.), Concerning the Prevention of Decay in Peach Trees, 1797 Dec. 26.
    - Report of Committee on Turner's paper on the prairie squirrel, 1798 June 22; 1.0 item; American Philosophical Society. (Box 1)
    - Report of Committee on Varle's canal locks, 1807 Mar. 20; 1.0 item; American Philosophical Society. (Box 1)
      See Varle to Caspar Wistar, 1806 Nov. 20 and B. H. Latrobe to C. W. Peale, 1807 Mar. 4
      Mechanics, Machinery, Engineering, etc.
    - Report of Committee on Vauquelin's Papers, 1810 Mar. 16; 1.0 item; American Philosophical Society. (Box 1)
      See Vauquelin, A.: "Analysis of the Nicotina Latifolia" 1809 Jan 12, and "Analysis of Snuff" 1809 Sept. 15
    - Report of Committee on This Paper, 1816 Nov. 15; American Philosophical Society. (Box 1)
      See "Concerning the Calculation of Surd Decimal Fractions", 1816 Oct. 18
    - Report of Committee on X's Communication on Peachtrees, 1800 Oct. 2; American Philosophical Society. (Box 1)
      See X (pseud.) Concerning the Prevention of Decay in Peachtrees, 1797, Dec. 26
    - Report of Publications Committee on S.C. Walker's Paper, 1834 Aug. 6; American Philosophical Society. (Box 1)
      See Walker, Sears Cook: "Concerning the Longitude...", 1833 Oct. 18
    - ALS to David Rittenhouse, 1795 Aug.; 1.0 item; Americanus (Box 1)
      Enclosing Americanus, "A pall lever to be applied to the ends of ships"
    - Concerning an Improved Windlass, 1795 Sept. 18; 1.0 item; Americanus (pseud.) (Box 1)
      Originally enclosed with Americanus to Rittenhouse, 1795 Aug.
    - Analysis of the saline solution examined at the request of John Vaughan, n.d.; 1.0 item (Box 1)
    - ALS to John Vaughan, 1827 Nov. 7; 1.0 items; Anderson, Henry James (Box OS)
    - ALS to Robert Harris, 1773 Dec. 2; 1.0 item; Archer, John (Box 1)
    - ALS to Isaac Bartram, 1771 Nov. 15; 2.0 items; Archimedes, S. [i.e. Rednap Howell] (Box OS)
      See APS Archives 1772 Nov. 23
    - Concerning the prevention of water leaking into houses, 1805 Feb. 11; 1.0 item; Arnat, Thomas (Box OS)
    - Article on Warming Rooms, 1791 Mar. 7; 1.0 item (Box 1)
      Originally enclosed with Letter to David Rittenhouse, 1791, May 20.
    - ALS to the American Philosophical Society. President, 1816 May 9; 1.0 item; Austin, James (Box 1)
    - ALS to Robert Patterson, 1815 June 15; 1.0 item; Austin, James (Box 1)
    - ALS to John Vaughan, 1796 Sept. 20; 1.0 item; Aveilhi (Box 1)
      Relative to a cotton machine left with APS
    - ALS to the American Philosophical Society, 1806 Oct. 17; 1.0 item; Bache, William (Box 1)
    - An account of some experiments made on the habits of the vultures inhabiting Carolina, the turkey buzzard and the carrion crow, 1834 Jan. 20; 1.0 item; Bachman, John, 1790-1874 (Box 1)
    - ALS to John Vaughan, 1792 Sept. 21; 4.0 items; Barnes, Joseph (Box 1)
      On construction of mills
      Ills.
      note: Mill construction designs included.
    - Observations on the climate of New Orleans, 1817 May 22; 1.0 item; Barnwell, William (Box 1)
    - Concerning the ventilation of ships to prevent the rotting of timbers, 1825 Jan. 7; 1.0 item; Barron, James (Box 1)
    - Additional information on Phalaena tinea, 1812 Dec. 16; 1.0 item; Barton, Benjamin Smith, 1766-1815 (Box 1)
    - Cervus (article from Archaeologicae Americanae), 1806; 1.0 item; Barton, Benjamin Smith, 1766-1815 (Box 1)
      Article on animals of America. Refers to his name for elk, Cervus wapiti, derived from the Shawanese.
      Freeman and Smith 3669
    - Concerning Dunbar's paper on swallows, 1803 Jan. 21; 1.0 item; Barton, Benjamin Smith, 1766-1815 (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous facts concerning... the genus Bartonia, 1815 Dec. 15; 1.0 item; Barton, Benjamin Smith, 1766-1815 (Box 1)
    - ALS to John Vaughan, 1801 April 1; 1.0 item; Barton, Benjamin Smith, 1766-1815 (Box 1)
    - ALS to John Vaughan, 1812 May 30; 1.0 item; Barton, William (Box 1)
    - ALS to John Vaughan, 1813 Feb. 9; 1.0 item; Barton, William (Box 1)
    - ALS to John Vaughan, 1813 Jan. 20; 1.0 item; Barton, William (Box 1)
    - Some Account of the Naked or Siberian Barley [printed broadside], 1771 July 19; 1.0 item; Bartram, Moses (Box 1)
    - Memoire sur le cotton-animal ou sur l'insecte porte-mouches, 1797 Jan. 3; 1.0 item; Baudry des Lozières, Louis Narcisse (Box 1)
      In French, with English translation
    - Concerning a theorem for ascertaining a standard measure, 1808; 1.0 item; Bennett (Box 1)
    - Concerning an operation on a boy; and, A singular case of chirurgo-medical operation in the Nosocomy of the University of Upsal in Sweden, 1800 Mar. 7-8; 2.0 items; Bergsten, Nicholas (Box 1)
      D. 11p. and 1 drawing and end. For report of committee, see: Report of committee...; May 2, 1800
    - Directions for putting up beef for exportation, 1805; 1.0 item; Berthoud, James & Co. (Box 1)
    - Directions for putting up beef for exportation, 1805; 1.0 item; Berthoud, James & Co. (Box 0.1)
      Copy in John Vaughan's hand
    - Bill of mortality of Portsmouth, New Hampshire, 1803; 1.0 item (Box 1)
      Originally enclosed in Lyman Spalding to John R. Coxe, 1803 Feb. 21
    - Researches on the cause of goiter in the mountains of New Granada, 1830 Oct.; 1.0 item; Boussingault, Jean Baptiste Joseph Diedonne (Box 1)
      Originally enclosed in Joaquim Acosta to APS Secretary, 1832 May 24.
    - The Comet: elements of the orbit of the comet now visible [printed circular], 1811 Dec. 6; 1.0 item; Bowditch, Nathaniel, 1773-1838 (Box 1)
    - LS Cy to American Philosophical Society, 1790 Sept. 30; 1.0 item; Bradford, William, 1719-1791 (Box 1)
      Transmitting an "extraordinary radish."
    - ALS to the Journal of Commerce. Editors, 1831 Feb. 10; 1.0 item; Bridgman, E. C., (Elijah Coleman), 1801-1861 (Box 1)
      Moral condition of Spanish possessions in Indian archipelago
    - ALS to Benjamin Franklin, 1789 July 4; 1.0 item; Brisbane, James (Box 1)
      Re: "discovery of longitude."
    - ALS to unidentified recipient, 1784 Nov. 6; 1.0 item; Brooks, Ebenezer (Box 1)
      Discovery of perpetual motion by Dr. McKinley of Kentucky.
    - ALS to John Vaughan, 1814 July 30; 3.0 items; Brown, Charles (Box 1)
      Astronomical observations.
      Ill.
      note: 2 astronomical drawings.
    - Map of the nitre caves of Kentucky, 1805 Feb. 7; 1.0 map, 37.6 x 22.9 cm; Brown, Samuel (Box OS)
      Natural History.
      This map was accompanied by an article by Brown published as "A description of a cave on Crooked creek, with remarks and observations on nitre and gun-powder." American Philosophical Society Transactions, vol. 6 (1809): pp. 235-247.
      Realms of Gold, 2 (1).
    - ALS to the American Philosophical Society, 1830 Nov. 29; 1.0 item; Browne, Peter Arrell (Box 1)
      Re: deficiencies in Maclure's geological map.
    - ALS to the American Philosophical Society, 1830 April 16; 1.0 item; Browne, Peter Arrell (Box 1)
      Sending curiosity: a piece of engraved marble recovered from quarry in Montgomery Co.
    - Concerning the simoom, n.d.; 1.0 item; Bruce, James (Box 1)
    - Concerning a vaccination, 1808 Feb. 19; 1.0 item; Buchanan, George (Box 1)
    - Concerning the propelling of vessels by siphon, 1819 Aug. 16; 1.0 item; Busby, C. Augustin (Box 1)
      llus.
    - Concerning the propelling of vessels by siphon (2), 1819 Aug. 16; 1.0 item; Busby, C. Augustin (Box 1)
      Note: Includes diagram of reservoir.
    - A method proposed which it is apprehended will be an improvement in finding the longitude at sea, 1788 June 19; 1.0 item; Byrnes, Daniel (Box 1)
    - ALS to Benjamin Franklin, 1788 Aug. 15; 1.0 item; Byrnes, Daniel (Box 1)
    - Recherches sur l'asterie des anciens, et remarque d'un caractere singulier que la taille a devoile sur un Grenat, 1807; 1.0 item; Caire-Morand, Antoine (Box 1)
    - ALS to Thomas Jefferson, 1807 Mar. 20; 1.0 item; Caire-Morand, Antoine (Box 1)
    - ALS to Stephen Harriman Long, 1819 Mar. 8; 1.0 item; Calhoun, John C. (Box 1)
      Orders to assume command of Long Expedition. Originally enclosed in Calhoun to Robert Walsh, 1819 Mar. 11
    - ALS to Robert Walsh, 1819 Mar. 11; 1.0 item; Calhoun, John C. (Box 1)
      Originally enclosing Calhoun to Stephen Harriman Long, 1819 Mar. 8
    - ALS to the American Philosophical Society. Description of a new invented Steam-Boat, 1810 Mar. 20; 2.0 items; Chapman, Isaac A. (Box 1)
      With sketch
      Chapman sent this communication to member James Mease to be presented to the Society for the possible award of a premium. Originally enclosed in Chapman to Mease, 1810 May 1. See also Robert Patterson Re: Chapman's steam boat, 1810 July 27
      - Imaginary river to illustrate the movement of Chapman's "new-invented Steam Boat", 1810 Mar. 20; 1.0 map, 19 x 30.5 cm; Chapman, Isaac A.
        Realms of Gold, 2 (3).
    - ALS to James Mease, 1810 May 1; 1.0 item; Chapman, Isaac A. (Box 1)
      Originally enclosing Chapman to APS, 1810 Mar. 20.
    - ALS to Robert Patterson, 1819 Dec. 15; 1.0 item; Chapman, Josiah (Box 1)
      See also Chapman to Robert Patterson, 1819 Aug. 31 (APS Archives).
    - Receipt to B.H. Latrobe, 1802 Jan. 4; Chesapeake & Delaware Canal (Box 1)
      See Tousard, Louis: "An Inquiry...", 1802 Jan. 4
    - ALS to Leonard Snowden, 1804 Oct. 8; 1.0 item; Chipchase, John (Box 1)
      Extracts on meteors.
    - Theory of magnetism, 1787 Feb. 7; 1.0 item; Churchman, John, 1753-1805 (Box 1)
    - Theory of magnetism (2), 1787 Feb. 7; 1.0 item; Churchman, John, 1753-1805 (Box 1)
    - ALS to the American Philosophical Society, 1787 May 4; 1.0 item; Churchman, John, 1753-1805 (Box 1)
      Requesting a report on his memorial.
    - ALS to the American Philosophical Society, 1787 Aug. 16; 1.0 item; Churchman, John, 1753-1805 (Box 1)
    - ALS to Benjamin Franklin, 1789 Mar. 21; 1.0 item; Churchman, John, 1753-1805 (Box 1)
      Regarding support for testing theory of magnetism as method of determining longitude.
    - ALS to John Vaughan, 1829 Nov. 23; 1.0 item; Clibborn, Edward (Box 1)
      Re: electricity.
    - ALS Cy extract to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1811 Sept. 4; 1.0 item; Clifford, John D. (Box 1)
      Nitre caves in Kentucky.
    - An attempt to ascertain the fusing temperature of metals, 1814 May 20; 1.0 item; Cloud, Joseph (Box 1)
    - Concerning the healthiness of Philadelphia, 1802; 1.0 item; Clymer, George (Box 1)
    - Description of a new hydrostatic balance, 1822 July 1; 2.0 items; Coates, Dr. (Box 1)
      Illus.
    - Remarks on some obvious phenomena of light, 1771 June 21; 1.0 item; Colden, Cadwallader, 1688-1776 (Box 1)
    - ALS to the President of the American Philosophical Society, 1793 Jan. 18; 1.0 item; Collin, Nicholas (Box 1)
      Re: climate of Pennsylvania.
    - ALS to John Vaughan, 1826 Mar. 16; 1.0 item; Collins, Zaccheus, 1764-1831 (Box 1)
      Re: Mexican insect. Originally enclosing Taylor, Sicard and Co. to the APS, 1826 Jan. 20.
    - Concerning a new instrument for describing ellipses, 1819 Dec. 3; 1.0 item (Box OS)
    - Concerning a Relief for Sore Eyes, 1809 Oct.; 1.0 item (Box 2)
      From London, describes a cure of inflamed eyes.
    - Concerning Articles which may be Usefullly Introduced Among Rude Nations in Africa, n.d.; 1.0 item (Box 2)
      Re: introduction into Africa certain items from Europe.
    - Concerning Captain Swift's Observations on the Natives of the North West Coast of America, 1805 June 9; 1.0 item (Box 2)
      Notes of four voyages of Boston sea captain: description of houses and their ornamentation; mentions slitting of lower lip for decoration.
      Freeman and Smith 2434
    - Concerning Certain Grasses ... for Cattle, 1805 Sept.; 1.0 item (Box 2)
    - Concerning Cultivable Lands, 1819 Aug. 20; 1.0 item (Box 2)
    - Concerning Education in Pennsylvania, Ca. 1797; 1.0 item (Box 2)
    - Concerning Education in Public Schools, ca. 1797; 1.0 item (Box 2)
    - Concerning the Benefits of Stripping the Bark from Certain Diseased Orchard Trees, 1802 June 7; 1.0 item (Box 2)
    - Concerning the calculations of surd decimal fractions; [read]., 1816 Oct. 18; 1.0 item (Box 2)
      On last page is APS Report of Committee on this Papers, 1816 Nov. 15, signed by Robert M. Patterson.
    - Concerning the contents of vol. 1, American Philosophical Society Transactions, ca.1771; 1.0 item (Box 2)
    - Concerning the Currents through the Straits of Gibralter, n.d.; 1.0 item (Box 2)
    - Concerning the reduction of expenses of public officers, 1785 Spring; 1.0 item (Box 2)
    - Concerning Wire Fences, 1817; 1.0 item (Box 2)
    - Act of incorporation, 1799; 1.0 item; Connecticut Academy of Arts and Sciences (Box 2)
    - List of officers, 1799 Oct.; 1.0 item; Connecticut Academy of Arts and Sciences (Box 2)
    - ALS to Adam Seybert, 1799 Dec. 25; 1.0 item; Connecticut Academy of Arts and Sciences (Box 2)
    - An essay on the vermilion colour of Blood, and on the different colours of the metallic oxides, with an application of these principles to the arts, 1806 June 10; 1.0 item; Conover, Samuel Forman (Box 2)
    - ALS to Robert Hare, 1830 June 15; 1.0 item; Conrad, Solomon W. (Box 2)
      Originally enclosing S. H. Saunders, Concerning light, 1830 May 21.
    - Singular phenomenon [concerning phosphorescence], 1837 Aug. 9; 1.0 item; Conyngham, Redmond, 1781-1846 (Box 2)
    - Using the expression of 'transverse' [Pr. Circular letter], 1835 Nov.; 2.0 items; Cooper, Edward Joshua (Box 2)
      With engr. of Halley's comet.
    - ALS to Humphry Davy, 1818 Sept. 9; 1.0 item; Cooper, Thomas (Box 2)
      On tests of poisons.
    - ALS to unidentified recipient [on tests of poisons], 1818 Sept. 18; 1.0 item; Cooper, Thomas (Box 2)
      With partial copy.
    - ALS to unidentified recipient [on tests of poisons], 1818 Sept. 18; 1.0 item; Cooper, Thomas (Box 2)
      Partial copy.
    - On boiling sugar, 1801; 1.0 item; Cooper, Thomas (Box OS)
    - On the tests of arsenic, 1818 Sept. 18; 1.0 item; Cooper, Thomas (Box 2)
    - Syllabus of the Lectures of ...on Geological and Mineralogy in the University of Pennsylvania [Pr. Broadside], 1.0 item; Cooper, Thomas (Box 2)
    - ALS to the American Philosophical Society [concerning a new street lamp], 1797 Jan. 7; 1.0 item; Couldery, William (Box 2)
    - ALS to Thomas Jefferson, 1797 Dec. 4; 1.0 item; Coulter, Thomas (Box 2)
      Re: preventing premature death in peach trees.
    - Article on premature death of peach trees, n.d.; Coulter, Thomas (Box 2)
      Notes: c.f. A.P.S.: Report of Committee on the Preservation of Peach Trees 1798, April 4. C.f. Minutes: pp. 24, 269, 303. Enclosed originally with letter from Coulter to T. Jefferson; 1797 Dec. 4.
    - ALS to John Vaughan, 1832 Sept. 20; 1.0 item; Coxe, John Redman, 1773-1864 (Box 2)
      Re Colchicum.
    - Plan for a fan chair, 1786 Aug. 18; 5.0 items; Cram, John (Box 2)
      Illustr. and explanation by Charles Willson Peale. See Peale to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1786 July 31 (Barton Papers).
    - ALS to the Secretary of the American Philosophical Society, 1817 May 27; 1.0 item; Crane, Gabriel (Box 2)
      Re: grub found in a state of vegetation.
    - Observations to serve for the mineralogical map of the state of Maryland, 1809 Jan. 20; 1.0 item; Creswell, Charles (Box 2)
      Re. Godon's map.
    - ALS to Thomas Jefferson, 1809 Jan. 20; 1.0 item; Creswell, Charles (Box 2)
    - ALS to Society of Friends, 1829 June 10; 1.0 item; Crivelli, M. (Box 2)
      The potato as counter to poverty.
    - ALS to James Cutbush, 1814 July 1; 1.0 item; Croker, A. (Box 2)
      On the conversion of a vertical into a rotary motion.
    - ALS to Benjamin Franklin, 1787 June 11; 1.0 item; Croker, Temple Henry (Box 2)
      On the magnetic needle.
    - Concerning the Causes of Animal Heat, 1816 Jan. 19; 1.0 item; Currie, William (Box 2)
    - Remarks on such of the experiments of Mr. Daniel Ellis of Edinburgh have a tendency to disprove the generally received doctrine of the causes of animal heat, 1797 April 7; 1.0 item; Currie, William (Box 2)
    - Remarks on the effects of Perkins' metallic rods in the cure of diseases, 1797 April 7; 1.0 item; Currie, William (Box 2)
    - ALS to John Vaughan, 1818 June 2; 2.0 items; Currie, William (Box 2)
      "A sketch of some of the errors, which have been discovered in some of the philosophical opinions of the illustrious Sir Isaac Newton."
    - ALS to John Vaughan (2), 1818 June 2; 1.0 item; Currie, William (Box 2)
    - Concerning Arequipa, Peru, and surrounding area, 1819 May 21; 1.0 item; Curson, S. (Box 2)
      Author describes a climb of Mount Yachi, near Arequipa. Discusses Quechua concept of oxygen deficiency, to them a faintness due to "antimonal loads"; mentions attitude of Indians joining climb toward revelation of mine locations.
      Freeman and Smith 3104.
    - Concerning Arequipa, Peru, and surrounding area (2), 1819 May 21; 1.0 item; Curson, S. (Box 2)
      Author describes a climb of Mount Yachi, ner Arequipa. Discusses Queachua concept of oxygen dificiency, to them a faintness due to "antimonal loads": mentions attitude of Indians joining climb toward revelation of mine locations.
    - Thermometrical journal, 1800 Dec. 16-1801 May 12; 1.0 item; Cutbush, Edward (Box OS)
      Originally enclosed in Cutbush to John Vaughan, 1801 July 10.
    - ALS to John Vaughan, 1801 July 10; 1.0 item; Cutbush, Edward (Box 2)
      Originally enclosing Cutbush, Thermometrical journal.
    - ALS to John Vaughan, 1832 June 1; 1.0 item; Cuthbert, John (Box 2)
    - ALS to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1792 Aug. 31; 1.0 item; Cutler, Manasseh, 1742-1823 (Box 2)
      Report on age of Ohio mounds using tree-ring dating.
      Freeman and Smith 1207.
    - Economy and comfort introduced to the fire-side, or, a hint for saving fuel and procuring a remedy for smoky chimneys, 1796 Dec. 16; 1.0 item; D.B.T.P.S. (pseud) (Box 2)
    - ALS to Thomas Jefferson, 1808 June 20; 1.0 item; Dabney, John B. (Box 2)
      Re: volcano at Fayal, Madeira.
    - Concerning Mill Grove lead mine in Pennsylvania, 1805 June 15; 2.0 items; Da Costa, Francis (Box 2)
    - Statement of the discovery of Mill Grove lead mine on Perkiomen Creek near Philadelphia, 1809 Nov. 18; 1.0 item; Da Costa, Francis (Box 2)
    - ALS to John Vaughan, 1832 May 9; 1.0 item; Dahlgren, John Adolphus Bernard (Box 2)
    - Succinct account of the respective charges and profits, in manufacturing hemp after his improved method, 1792 Dec. 9; 1.0 item; Dandiran (Box 2)
      Originally enclosed in Valltravers to APS President, 1792 Dec. 13.
    - ALS to the American Philosophical Society, n.d.; 1.0 item; Dannery, S. (Box 2)
      In French.
    - ALS to Robert Patterson, 1788 April 7; 2.0 items; Davidson, Robert (Box 2)
      On a teratological calf. Illus.
    - ALS to John Vaughan, 1819 May 12; 1.0 item; Davis, John, 1755-1783 (Box 2)
    - The Barbary powers and Sardinia and the situation of Italy generally, 1820 June 17; 1.0 item; Deabbate, Gaspard (Box 2)
    - Concerning the religious cult of the Vaudois [Waldensians], 1823 May 29; 1.0 item; Deabbate, Gaspard (Box OS)
      Originally enclosed in Deabbate to Robert Walsh, 1823 May 29.
    - ALS to Robert Walsh, 1823 May 29; 1.0 item; Deabbate, Gaspard (Box 2)
      Originally enclosing Deabbate, Concerning the religious of the Vaudois.
    - Cure for the croup, 1808 Mar. 13; 1.0 item; Dean, Mrs (?) (Box 2)
    - ALS to the American Philosophical Society, 1803 Feb. 4; 1.0 item; Dearborn, Benjamin (Box 2)
      Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. Enc. of 7p. Concerning the abolition of slavery. Cf. Minutes, p. 338.
      Biographical/Historical note
      Dearborn was an educator and an inventor.
    - Method of splitting stones by wedges, 1801; 1.0 item; Dearborn, Henry, 1751-1829 (Box 2)
    - ALS to Thomas Jefferson, 1804 Dec. 28; 1.0 item; Demaree, Samuel R. (Box 2)
      Proposal to form society to "alter and improve the orthography of the language of the United States."
    - Progres de l'enseignement mutuel en Dannemarck, 1827 Jan. 28; 1.0 item; Denmark (Box OS)
    - Description of a Stove, 1797 Nov. 3; 1.0 item (Box OS)
      Note: c.f. minutes, page 262.
    - ALS to Benjamin Rush, 1807 April 25; 1.0 item; DeWitt, Simeon (Box 2)
      Observations on the eclipse of 1806 June 16.
    - 2 Pr. Circulars to John Vaughan, 1825 Nov. 24; 3.0 items; DeWitt, Simeon (Box 2)
      Request for mineralogical information for University of the State of New York.
    - Extracts of notes... concerning a testaceous mass from Anastasia Island, Florida, 1823 July 10; 1.0 item; Dietz, R. (Box 2)
    - ALS to Joseph Correa de Serra, 1817 Oct. 1; 1.0 item; Drake, Daniel (Box 2)
      On the geology of the Ohio Valley.
    - ALS to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1803 Sept. 9; 2.0 items; Drayton, John (Box 2)
      On insect infestation and destruction of pine trees. Includes newspaper clipping.
    - Meteorological observations, 1803 May 1-31; 1.0 item; Duffield, Samuel (Box OS)
    - Plan of the nitre cave described by Dr. Samuel Brown, 1805; 1.0 map, 41.3 x 51.4 cm; Dufour, John James (Box OS)
      The cartouche reads: "A Survey of the Great Salt Petre Cave on Crooked Creek Madison County, Ky. by John James Dufour. 1805."
      See Samuel Brown, Map of the nitre cave of Kentucky, 1805 Feb. 7.
      Realms of Gold, 2 (2).
    - ALS to Thomas Jefferson, 1810 May 9; 1.0 item; Du Jareau, G. (Box 2)
    - Address to the citizens of New Orleans and to the members of the city council [newspaper clipping], 1808 Sept. 12-20; 2.0 items; Du Jareau, J. (Box 2)
      On levee and course of river in New Orleans.
    - ALS to Peter Stephen Duponceau [Pr. Circular letter "Interesting galvanic experiments"], 1833 July 19; 1.0 item; Dunbar, John R. W. (Box 2)
      On effects of galvanism on dead body of "Negro Ben." From the Winchester Virginian, 1833 June 27.
    - ALS to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1803 Jan. 7; 1.0 item; Dunbar, Robert (Box 2)
      See also Barton, Conerning Dunbar's paper on swallows, 1803 Jan. 21; APS, Report... 1803 Feb. 4 (APS Archives).
    - Astronomical observations made at the Forest near Natchez [re: solar eclipse of June 16, 1806], 1806 Aug. 15; 1.0 item; Dunbar, William, 1749-1810 (Box 2)
    - Monthly and annual results of meteorological observations made at the Forest 4 miles east of the river Mississippi, 1804 April 6; 1.0 item; Dunbar, William, 1749-1810 (Box 2)
    - ALS extract to John Vaughan, 1810; 1.0 item; Dunbar, William, 1749-1810 (Box 2)
      Re: spinning machine. See Winpenny and Long, Concerning a spinning machine, ca.1810.
    - ALS to John Vaughan, 1828 Dec. 17; 1.0 item (Box 2)
      On verso is John Vaughan, Memorandum concerning Rafn's communication about Norse relics in North America, 1828 December
    - ALS to John Vaughan, 1829 June 1; 1.0 item (Box 2)
    - ALS to John Vaughan, 1831 April 18; 1.0 item (Box 2)
      Re: American silk.
    - ALS to John Vaughan, 1803 Jan. 18; 1.0 item; Du Pont de Nemours, Eleuthere Irenee (Box 2)
      On asphyxia and causes of sudden death.
    - ALS to John Vaughan, 1805 Sept. 19; 1.0 item; Du Pont de Nemours, Eleuthere Irenee (Box 2)
      Comments on yellow fever. In French.